

Fahad Talpur

Software Engineer



Professional Summary

Self-motivated Software Engineer adds high level of experience over more than 2 years collaborating and working on multiple web, desktop and mobile based projects using React, ElectronJS and React-Native. Passionate, hardworking coder with penchant for developing customised interfaces that factor in unique demands for accessibility, reachability and security. Organised approach to meeting multiple, concurrent deadlines. Pulls from active knowledge of current technology landscape to promote best practices in web and mobile app design.



Work History

2019-01 -Current

Software Engineer

Trukkr Pvt. Ltd., Karachi, Sindh

- Used React JS for Multiple web applications with AntD and MaterialUI,
- Developed multiple mobile application using react-native.
- Maintaining and enhancing Front-end side.
- Write reusable components for both ReacrJS and React-native.
- Used Redux with Both ReactJS and React-native.
- Implemented Custom **animations** in React-Native.
- Backend Integration and data management logic.
- Used React JS for templating for faster compilation and developing reusable components.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Developing, Directing and Leading Front-end side



Address

Karachi, Sindh, 74600

Phone

331 280 3306

E-mail

fahadmirtalpur@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mir-fahad-talpur-6a72a

WWW

https://github.com /MirFahad58



Reactis

React-native

ElectronJs

Redux

••••

HTML, css & JavaScript



Ant Design, Material Ui & Native-Base

••••

Git control

••••

Socket.io client

••••

Firebase



with juniors.

 Gathered and defined project requirements to develop clear specifications for creating well-organized project plans.

2020-03 -Current

Front End Developer (remote)

Etats.sg, Singapore, Singapore

- Used React JS for web application admin panel with MaterialUI,
- Developed mobile application using react-native.
- Write reusable components for both ReacrJS and React-native.
- Used Redux with Both ReactJS and React-native.
- Implemented Google maps and other third party libraries in React-Native.
- Implemented Custom **animations** in React-Native.
- Backend Integration and data management logic.
- Used React JS for templating for faster compilation and developing reusable components.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.

2018-10 -2019-01

React and React-Native Intern

CIC-hub, Hyderabad, Sindh

- Front-end with react-native.
- Worked on Admob with React Native Guide.
- Developed Motivational Alarm Clock App.
- Learned core of React and React-Native.



Projects

- Transporter and Corporate Panel (portal.trukkr.pk).
 - Vehicle management section.
 - Driver management section.
 - Client management section.
 - Trip booking and management section.
 - User role based system.
 - Trukkr Shipper/User web panel.
 - Trip booking and management section.
 - Tracking System.

- Trukkr trip tracking system.
- Trukkr user mobile application.
- Trukkr driver mobile application.
- Trukkr Transporter mobile application.
- Customer suport panel (csp.trukkr.pk).
- Geo Attendance Admin panel (Ettats.sg)
- Geo Attenance brand promoter mobile application.



Education

2015-01 -2018-10

Bachelor of Engineering: Software Engineering

Mehran University Of Engineering & Technology lamshoro



Personal projects

• Online Document Validation

Aims to facilitate institutes, organizations & corporate entities.

Provide interface for employees to verify student information.

Provide interface for end users to check certificate using key or QR code.

- Cane Trade Manager Cane Trade data management software. technologies (Electron, React, neDB).
- MemorizeMe

Detail of Image with QR-code to remember the memory. technologies (Android, Java)

- Would you rather technologies (React, Redux)
- Instagram UI clone technologies (React-native, Redux)
- Offensive words detector offensive words detection at real time react and nodejs